<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.0/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>Architecture and Overview of the Perl XPCOM Interface</title>
  <sect1>
    <title>Objectives of Perl XPCOM</title>
    <para>With support for languages such as C++, Java, JavaScript, and Python,
one may ask, "why an XPCOM interface to Perl?" The answer is quite simple, Perl
is one of the most widely used scripting languages around. It is also well known 
for the wide variety of extension modules and libraries available for it. By
making use of XPCOM, developers can create libraries of native class objects and 
have them instantly accessible to the Perl interpreter, without the need writing 
custom bindings with tools such as XS and SWIG. This alone is enough reason to 
justify the existence of XPCOM support for Perl. Such a tool is particularly
advantageous to developers using perl as an embedded interpreter to provide
scripting capabilities in a larger application, which was the initial impetus
for creating this extension.
</para>
    <para>By adding the capability to implement XPCOM interfaces in Perl,
the language becomes a first class citizen in the XPCOM world. Perl's
flexibility allows for the quick implementation of interfaces, making it useful
for both prototyping components and for use as a RAD tool.</para>
    <sect2>
      <title>Current Limitations of the Perl XPCOM Interface</title>
      <para>In the current implementation of the XPCOM interface for Perl, the
following functionality is not implemented:
<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>Array arguments (e.g. [array, size_is(n)] in string foo) are
not fully supported. Support for calling methods with array input arguments
works, but array outputs ar enot implemented yet, nor is the ability to
implement methods with array arguments in Perl.</para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>Perl XPCOM components must run in one thread only. Threads can 
be invoked (e.g. creating instances of <literal>nsIRunnable</literal> and
dispatching them to an <literal>nsIThread</literal> or
<literal>nsIThreadPool</literal> works, but Perl code itself cannot be executed
in multiple threads. This is because Perl itself is not entirely thread safe, so 
this situation is not likely to change. Assume a general warning of 'There Be
Dragons Here' when dealing with threads in Perl. Any help in better
understanding threading with regard to Perl would be appreciated.</para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
</para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Using XPCOM Components from Perl</title>
    <para>The Perl XPCOM extension is provided as a standard Perl module. This
module allows access to the XPCOM library and XPCOM components from Perl. The
module is named, simply enough, XPCOM. In reality, this module defines several
packages, they are simply all packaged into a single module for simplicity,
since nearly all the packages are required for nearly any use of the
extension.</para>
    <sect2>
      <title>The Components Package</title>
      <para>The package named <literal>Components</literal> in the XPCOM
extension provides Perl's interface to the XPCOM libraries component
manager. Through this package, new objects are instantiated and component
services are obtained. In addition, all global XPCOM actions reside under the
Components namespace.</para>
      <note>
	<para>Originally, the Components package resided under the
<literal>XPCOM::Components</literal> namespace. Despite being the proper way for 
arranging the namespaces in such a package, it was quickly decided that it was
too verbose to be practical.</para>
      </note>
      <para>The following functions and variables are defined under the
Components package:
<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><link linkend="components.classes.interfaces"><varname>%Components::classes</varname></link> - A hash variable
containing all registered classes.</para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><link linkend="components.classes.interfaces"><varname>%Components::interfaces</varname></link> - A hash variable
containing all registered interfaces.</para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><link linkend="components.retcodes"><varname>$Components::returnCode</varname></link> - A scalar variable 
containing the return code set by the last call to an XPCOM subroutine or method 
of an XPCOM component.</para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><link linkend="components.classes.interfaces"><methodname>Components::Classes($anID)</methodname></link> - A
subroutine which obtains component classes by contract ID.</para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><link linkend="components.classes.interfaces"><methodname>Components::Interfaces($anIFace)</methodname></link> - A
subroutine which obtains interfaces by name.</para>
	  </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para><link
linkend="components.constructor"><methodname>Components::Constructor($contractID, 
$iid)</methodname></link> - Convenience method for creating an object and
performing a QueryInterface call on it.</para>
	    </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><link linkend="components.retcodes"><methodname>Components::isSuccessCode($nsresult)</methodname></link>
- Returns a boolean true or false if the given return code is a success code or not.</para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><link linkend="components.getservice"><methodname>Components::GetService($cid, $iid)</methodname></link> -
Obtains a service from the service manager by contract ID and interface ID.</para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para><methodname>Components::ID($idString)</methodname> - Creates
an <literal>nsID</literal> object from a uuid string.</para>
	  </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para><methodname>Components::Manager()</methodname> - This method 
returns a handle on the global component manager.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para><link linkend="components.wrapobject"><methodname>Components::WrapObject($obj, $iid)</methodname></link>
- Wraps a perl blessed object in an XPCOM interface. This should generally be
avoided except for certain cases, which will be covered further on.</para>
	    </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
</para>
      <sect3 id="components.classes.interfaces">
	<title>The Components::classes and Components::interfaces Hashes</title>
	<para>The classes and interfaces hashes within the Components package
provide convenient access points to XPCOM objects. They are actually implemented 
as tied hashes to the Components::Classes and Components::Interfaces
subroutines. The classes hash takes a contract ID string as a key and returns an 
instance of the class matching that ID or <literal>undef</literal> if no such
class exists. The interfaces hash takes an interface name as a key and returns
an <literal>nsID</literal> object representing the interface or
<literal>undef</literal> if no such interface exists.</para>
	<para>The classes and interfaces hashes are only thin wrappers around
Components::Classes() and Components::Interfaces(). The key values of the two
hashes are simply passed as the argument to their tied subroutines. The hashes
exist, and are encouraged to be the preferred means of access, to be more
conformant to the approach used in Mozilla's JavaScript XPCOM
implementation.</para>
	<para>The following example demonstrates how to use the classes and
interfaces hashes to obtain instances of XPCOM components which can them be used 
from Perl.</para>
	<figure id="xp-perl.example1">
	  <title>Creating an instance of an XPCOM component</title>
	  <programlisting><![CDATA[#!/usr/bin/perl
use XPCOM;

# Create an instance of of an object. The value returned supports 
# the nsISupports interface implicitly
my $class = $Components::classes{'@mozilla.org/sample;1'};

# Call QueryInterface on the class to get a handle on it in the interface 
# we want.
my $iface = $class->QueryInterface($Components::interfaces{nsISample});

# We now have a usable object which we can invoke interface methods on.
$iface->writeValue("Hello World!");
]]>
</programlisting>
	</figure>
	  <para>The method of object creation in the previous example is the
formal way of creating an instance of an XPCOM object. As a convenience, you may 
use the <literal id="components.constructor">Components::Constructor()</literal> method, which takes a
contract ID string and an interface ID as its arguments.</para>
      </sect3>
      <sect3 id="components.retcodes">
	<title>Checking the Status of Method Calls</title>
	<para>The Perl XPCOM package provides a standardized means of reporting
the success or failure of an action using XPCOM's error code system. The return
code of all calls to the Components package and the return code of any method of 
an XPCOM object goes into <literal>$Components::returnCode</literal> and is
valid until the next call to another XPCOM method. This behavior can be relied
upon by the programmer, any deviation from this behavior is an error that needs
to be corrected. In addition, the Components package has the convention of
returning <literal>undef</literal> in the event of an error in calls to any of
its members.</para>
	<para>The Components::isSuccessCode() subroutine provides a convenience
mechanism for checking whether a return code is a success or failure return
code. In addition, the major XPCOM return code values have defined constants
under the <literal>Components::results::</literal> namespace. The following
example code demonstrates checking a return for success or failure and dealing
with specific return values.</para>
	<figure>
	  <title>XPCOM Return Code Handling</title>
	  <programlisting><![CDATA[#!/usr/bin/perl
use XPCOM;

my $class = $Components::classes{'@mozilla.org/sample;1'};

# the classes hash will return undef if no class exists for the contract ID, 
# so just die here if we have no class.
if(!defined($class)) die "Unable to create instance of class.";

my $iface = $class->QueryInterface($Components::interfaces{nsISample});
# Check the return code if we succeeded
if(Components::isSuccessCode($Components::returnCode)) {
  $iface->writeValue("Hello World!");
} else {
  # Now check if is a no interface error or something else.
  if($Components::returnCode == Components::results::NS_NOINTERFACE) {
    die "Class does not support the nsISample interface.";
  } else {
    die "Ack! Some unexpected error occurred.";
  }
}
]]></programlisting>
	</figure>
      </sect3>
      <sect3 id="components.getservice">
	<title>Accessing Services</title>
	<para>Access to the XPCOM service manager is provided through the
<literal>Components::GetService</literal> subroutine. This is used for obtaining 
handles on global component objects, referred to as services. An example of a
service would be the category manager. The next example demonstrates how to
obtain a handle on the category manager.</para>
	<figure>
	  <title>Obtaining a service object</title>
	  <programlisting><![CDATA[#!/usr/bin/perl
use XPCOM;

# Fetch a service by providing the contract ID of the service components and 
# its interface ID. GetService sets returnCode accordingly and will return undef
# on failure.
my $service = Components::GetService('@mozilla.org/categorymanager;1',
                                                        $Components::interfaces{nsICategoryManager});
if(Components::isSuccessCode($Components::returnCode)) {
  $service->addCategoryEntry("foo", "bar", "baz", 1, 1);
}
]]></programlisting>
	</figure>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
      <title>The nsISupports Package</title>
      <para>Perl XPCOM implements access to component objects through the
nsISupports package. All XPCOM components in Perl are blessed into this
package. Much like XPCOM's nsISupports interface, the nsISupports package can
point to any component. Accessing component methods and attributes looks much like it would in
C++ or JavaScript.</para>
      <sect3>
	<title>Component Method Access</title>
	<para>As mentioned, calling a method on an XPCOM object is pretty
straight forward. Method names match the names defined in an interface's IDL
description in terms of case sensitivity. In a previous <link
linkend="xp-perl.example1">example</link>, accessing the method 
<methodname>writeValue</methodname> from the <literal>nsISample</literal>
interface is demonstrated. Where Perl deviates from the method invokation
conventions seen in other languages, C++ for example, all method argument
specified as <literal>out</literal> arguments in the IDL definition are returned 
in a list context as the return value of the method call. For example, take the
following interface:</para>
	<programlisting><![CDATA[
interface nsIFoo : nsISupports {
  void myMethod(in string foo, in short bar, out string baz, out short bang);
};
]]></programlisting>
	<para>In Perl calling the method, <methodname>myMethod</methodname> on
an object implementing the <literal>nsIFoo</literal> interface would look like
this:</para>
	<programlisting><![CDATA[
# Arguments baz and bang are output arguments, so they are returned as a list.
  my ($baz, $bang) = $aFoo->myMethod("foo", 5);
]]></programlisting>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
	<title>Using Interface Attributes</title>
	<para>Interface attributes are treated as subroutines in Perl. Any
attribute that allows its value to be set can be modified by calling a function
of the same name as the attribute with a single argument. Fetching the value of
an attribute is done by calling a function of the same name with no
arguments. The following example demonstrates this.</para>
	<programlisting><![CDATA[
# Example of setting and getting the value of attribute myAttribute from an
# object.

# Set myAttribute
  $anObject->myAttribute("Foo!");

# Get myAttribute's value
  my $value = $anObject->myAttribute();
]]></programlisting>
      </sect3>
      <sect3>
	<title>Accessing Interface Constants</title>
	<para>Constants defined by an interface can be accessed from the
interfaces has or via a perl XPCOM object.. Consider the
following interface:</para>
	<programlisting><![CDATA[
interface nsIFoo : nsISupports {
  const short MY_CONSTANT = 42;
};
]]></programlisting>
	<para>Accessing the value of <literal>MY_CONSTANT</literal> from the
interfaces hash or via an instance of an <literal>nsIFoo</literal> object would look like this:</para>
	<programlisting><![CDATA[
# Accessing from the interface directly
  my $value1 = $Components::interfaces{nsIFoo}->MY_CONSTANT;
# Access from an already created object.
  my $value2 = $aFoo->MY_CONSTANT;
]]></programlisting>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Implementing XPCOM Components in Perl</title>
      <sect2>
	<title>Creating a Perl Component Module</title>
	<para>XPCOM components implemented in Perl are created by writing Perl
modules which define packages that allow for registering and loading an XPCOM 
component (or components), as well as the implementation of the component. As
the motto for Perl is "There's More Than One Way To Do It", the same holds true
in creating XPCOM Perl modules, however this document is going to discuss only a 
single approach, which is the most straight forward approach and avoid resorting 
to too much confusion and trickery.</para>
	<para>The first step in creating a Perl XPCOM module is to create the
module bootstrapping package. The name of this package <emphasis>must</emphasis> 
be the same as the name of the module file it is written in that will reside in
XPCOM's components directory. By way of example, this document will walk through 
a Perl implementation of the nsISample interface that is included with the XPCOM
library as a demonstration. The first step is to create the module file,
<literal>nsSample.pm</literal>, and define the bootstrapping package
<literal>nsSample</literal>. The following figure shows the code of the nsSample 
package:</para>
	<figure>
	  <title>The nsSample bootstrapping package</title>
	  <programlisting><![CDATA[
package nsSample;
use strict;
use XPCOM;

sub GetModule {
  my ($compMgr, $fileSpec) = @_;
  my $module = new nsSample::Module;
  $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
  return $module;
}
]]></programlisting>
	</figure>
	<para>Programmers experienced with writing XPCOM modules in C++ will
probably notice that this package closely parallels the
<literal>NSGetModule</literal> function used by XPCOM's native component
loader. This is, in fact, the direct Perl equivalent. All Perl XPCOM modules
must implement a <literal>GetModule</literal> subroutine in a package matching
the same name as the module file. The perl component loader expects to find this 
subroutine and will not load the module unless it exists. The GetModule
subroutine is quite simple, it merely creates an instance of a perl object which 
implements the <classname>nsIModule</classname> interface for this module. In
keeping with the walkthrough example, the following figure lists the 
<literal>nsSample::Module</literal> package.</para>
	<figure>
	  <title>The nsSample::Module package</title>
	  <programlisting><![CDATA[
package nsSample::Module;
use strict;
use XPCOM;

sub new {
  my $self =
     {
       firstTime  => PR_TRUE,
       myCID      => Components::ID('{40a6de81-fac6-498e-b86d-d0f6063e4bdc}'),
       myProgID   => '@mozilla.org/perlsample;1',
       myFactory  => new nsSample::Factory()
     };
  bless $self, 'nsSample::Module';
  $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
  return $self;
}

sub registerSelf {
  my ($pkg, $compMgr, $fileSpec, $location, $type) = @_;
  if($pkg->{firstTime} == PR_TRUE) {
    $pkg->{firstTime} = PR_FALSE;
    $Components::returnCode =
      Components::results::NS_ERROR_FACTORY_REGISTER_AGAIN;
  }
  $compMgr->registerComponentWithType($pkg->{myCID},
                                      "Sample Perl Component",
                                      $pkg->{myProgID},
                                      $fileSpec,
                                      $location,
                                      PR_TRUE,
                                      PR_TRUE,
                                      $type);
 
  $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
}

sub getClassObject {
  my ($pkg, $compMgr, $cid, $iid) = @_;
  if(!$cid->equals($pkg->{myCID})) {
    $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_ERROR_NO_INTERFACE;
    return undef;
  }
  if(!$iid->equals($Components::interfaces{'nsIFactory'})) {
    $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_ERROR_NOT_IMPLEMENTED;
    return undef;
  }
  $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
  return $pkg->{myFactory};
}

]]></programlisting>
	</figure>
	<note>
	  <para>Notice the use of the PR_TRUE and PR_FALSE constants in the
example. The XPCOM module exports these symbols implicitly for convenience and
to keep code looking familiar to C++ component writers.</para>
	</note>
	<para>This example implements the required subroutines that any module
package must implement: a constructor, <methodname>registerSelf</methodname>,
and <methodname>getClassObject</methodname>. The module described does all the
basics necessary for a module, it defines a CID, and contract ID for the
component it provides, as well as a factory object for the component. It
registers the component with the component manager in 
<methodname>registerSelf</methodname>, and returns the component factory in 
<methodname>getClassObject</methodname>. This pattern of module implementation
closely follows the JavaScript method and should be practiced for
consistency. However, you are free to implement a module in any means preferred, 
e.g. Keeping the CID and contract ID in the factory package and referencing it
when registering the component, etc. This example registers only a single
component, however it is possible to have multiple components and/or
factories. The XPCOM perl package also comes with GenericModule and
GenericFactory packages which can be used to implement the module and factory
aspects of a component package quickly and easily.</para>
	<para>After the module package is implemented, the next step is to
define the component factory. The factory is responsible for creating new
instances of a component object. The next figure shows the code to an example
Perl factory package:</para>
	<figure>
	  <title>The nsSample::Factory Package</title>
	  <programlisting><![CDATA[package nsSample::Factory;
use strict;
use XPCOM;

sub new {
  my $self = {};
  bless $self, 'nsSample::Factory';
  $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
  return $self;
}

sub createInstance {
  my ($pkg, $outer, $iid) = @_;
  if($outer) {
    $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_ERROR_NO_AGGREGATION;
    return undef;
  }
  my $sample = new nsSample::SampleImpl();
  $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
  # Don't call QueryInterface on the object yet! The native wrapper around the 
  # perl factory class takes care of that. The object as it exists here is not 
  # a 'real' XPCOM object yet.
  return $sample;
}
]]></programlisting>
	</figure>
	<para>The factory implementation is pretty straight forward. In fact,
for nearly all cases, the GenericFactory package should be sufficient.</para>
	<para>The final step is to implement the actual component. This is where 
we finally get to the meat of the package, all the prior steps in our example
are fairly boilerplate tasks. The common factor shared among the actual
component implementation packages is that they must implement a constructor, and 
the <methodname>QueryInterface</methodname> method. The final figure in this
section shows the implementation of the sample component:</para>
	<figure>
	  <title>The nsSample::SampleImpl Package</title>
	  <programlisting><![CDATA[package nsSample::SampleImpl;
use strict;
use XPCOM;

sub new {
  my $self = { value  => '<default value>' };
  bless $self, 'nsSample::SampleImpl';
  $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
  return $self;
}

sub writeValue {
  my ($pkg, $aPrefix) = @_;
  print "nsSample::writeValue => $aPrefix".$pkg->{value}."\n";
  $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
}

sub value {
  my ($pkg, $aValue) = @_;
  if(defined($aValue)) {
    $pkg->{value} = $aValue;
  } else {
    return $pkg->{value};
  }
}

sub poke {
  my ($pkg, $aValue) = @_;
  $pkg->{value} = $aValue;
  $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
}

sub QueryInterface {
  my ($pkg, $iid) = @_;
  if(!$iid->equals($Components::interfaces{'nsISample'}) &&
     !$iid->equals($Components::interfaces{'nsISupports'})) {
    $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_ERROR_NO_INTERFACE;
  } else {
    $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
  }
  return $pkg;
}
]]></programlisting>
	</figure>
	<para>The important items to note in this example are the use of the
standard Perl convention of making the blessed object a hash reference in which
the objects attributes can be stored and the
<methodname>QueryInterface</methodname> method. For nearly all case, the format
of the example QueryInterface can apply to any component. Another item to take
note of is the example's <methodname>value</methodname> method. The 
<methodname>value</methodname> item is an attribute of the 
<interfacename>nsISample</interfacename> interface. Perl XPCOM treats interface
attributes as subroutines, much like C++, however, only one subroutine is
used. If the subroutine recieves an argument, then it is the setter method,
otherwise it is the getter method.</para>
      </sect2>
  </sect1>
    <sect1>
      <title>Assorted Implementation Idioms</title>
      <para>This section covers a grab bag of topics covering areas in which the 
behavior of this package may not follow exact XPCOM or Perl module conventions.</para>
      <sect2>
	<title>Convenience Macros</title>
	<para>To simplify and clarify Perl XPCOM programming, the package
provides the following macros for you to use.</para>

	      <para>PR_TRUE and PR_FALSE - Fairly self explanatory I
think. These macros exist to make the intent of code more clear, instead of 1
and 0 values.</para>

	      <para>NS_SUCCEEDED - This macro serves as a test facility for
checking the return values of XPCOM method calls. NS_SUCCEEDED is a shorthand
method of saying
<literal>Components::isSuccessCode($Components::returnCode)</literal>, which
obviously is a bit cumbersome and becomes a pain to type after about 100
times... The format of this macro fits well into the Perl style of programming
by making terminal error traps easy to do. For example:</para>
	<programlisting><![CDATA[
$anObject->someMethod();
die "Call to someMethod() failed." unless NS_SUCCEEDED;
]]></programlisting>
      </sect2>
      <sect2 id="components.wrapobject">
	<title>When Components::WrapObject() Isn't Cheating</title>
	<para>The XPCOM Perl module provides a method called
<literal>Components::WrapObject()</literal> which takes a blessed Perl scalar
and an interface ID as its arguments and returns the perl object wrapped in an
XPCOM object which is identified by the interface ID given. This function exists 
for two, and only two cases. The first case is for allowing a perl object which
implements an XPCOM interface to pass itself as an argument to another XPCOM
method. This requires a bit of explanation. In this package, when implementing
an XPCOM interface in Perl, you write a perl class like you would typically
write a perl class. The problem is that the Perl objects handle on itself within 
its own subroutines is the raw blessed perl object, not a pointer to an XPCOM
object. As a result the Perl object can't pass itself off as an XPCOM object to
a method of another XPCOM class without some help (look at the previous
nsSample::SampleImpl perl package example as a reference if I've lost you. I
know this explanation sucks.). By using the Components::WrapObject() method, a
perl class can pass an instance of itself as an argument. Using the nsSample
example as a reference, say that it wanted to notify an observer of some kind
that a method had been called. The observer's interface expects an nsISupports
pointer. This is how you'd do it:</para>
	<programlisting><![CDATA[
# An excerpt from the earlier nsSample::SampleImpl example
sub writeValue {
  my ($pkg, $aPrefix) = @_;
  # Notify some fictional observer we've been called. For the sake of
  # simplicity, this example pretends the observer is held as an
  # attribute of the object
  my $nsSELF = Components::WrapObject($pkg,
                                                           $Components::interfaces{nsISupports});
  $pkg->{myObserver}->observe("writeValue", $nsSELF);
  print "nsSample::writeValue => $aPrefix".$pkg->{value}."\n";
  $Components::returnCode = Components::results::NS_OK;
}
]]></programlisting>
	<para>The second situation where WrapObject is appropriate is the inline 
declaration of components. By that I mean for times where, if writing a program
in Perl which uses XPCOM and you want to expose part of the program to XPCOM by
defining some packages which implement XPCOM interfaces and a factory package to 
create instances of them that is registered when the script is run via
<methodname>nsIComponentManager::registerFactory()</methodname>. I have some
examples of this which I'll get merged into the docs shortly, along with a
better explanation Real Soon Now. :)</para>
	<para>The WrapObject method should <emphasis>not</emphasis> be used for
anything outside of these two cases. Not only would it be cheating, use outside
of the two cases I've mentioned will most likely result in stability problems.</para>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>
</chapter>
<!-- Keep this comment at the end of the file
Local variables:
mode: sgml
sgml-default-dtd-file:"/usr/local/share/xml/docbook-4.1.2/docbookxml.ced"
sgml-omittag:nil
sgml-shorttag:t
End:
-->
